good afternoon everyone so today we're
大家下午好所以我们今天跟
going to transition into a topic that to
要过渡到一个主题 ，以
me is sort of the reward for having
我是那种奖励对于具有
slugged through all the low-level stuff
通过所有 低层次的东西 猛击
you've done up to this point to be able
你做 了这 一点 ，能够
to really understand and become adept at
要 真正理解并能熟练地
programming network software not these
编程网络软件不是这些
are lots of networking that we're not
很多网络的，我们不是
going to cover but at least to have some
要覆盖，但至少 有一些
familiarity with it so I know that a lot
熟悉它，所以我知道很多
of you are sort of in the midst of
你是那种在之中
trying to figure out how to make Melek
试图找出如何使 梅莱克
run and make it run fast and so this
运行并使其运行速度快 ，所以这
this of topic is really more pointing
这个话题真的是越来越指点
toward the future but it's very relevant
面向 未来 ，但它是非常相关
to the final web you'll do for the
到最后的网页，你会在做
course and so we're starting to to get
当然， 等我们 开始得到
ready for that
准备好了
so like I said this course is not really
所以像我说， 这当然是不是真的
a full course in networking there's many
在网络全程有很多
other courses at the university that are
在大学其他课程 是
and so what we're going to try and do is
还等什么，我们要尝试做的是
give you just a little flavor of it and
给你的只是一点点味道和
particularly as everything in the course
特别是在使用过程中的一切
of programmers perspective so how you as
程序员的角度 怎么那么你作为
a software developer would make use of
软件开发者利用
the c-level api's that are relevant to
C级API的 是相关的
network programming yeah why isn't this
网络编程是啊，为什么 不这样
working
加工
so the idea behind most networking
因此， 大多数网络背后的想法
systems is what's called the
系统是所谓的
client-server model and the idea is that
客户端-服务器模型和想法是，
there's the service out there that you
有 在那里，你 的服务
want access to and you as a customer or
想获得和你的 客户 或
a client are making a request to that
客户机正在 为一个请求
server so an example would be when you
服务器，这样的 例子 是，当你
order something on Amazon Amazon has a
订购的东西在亚马逊 亚马逊拥有
bunch of servers and you go to your web
一堆服务器和你去你的网站
browser and content it contacts the
浏览器和内容 它接触
Amazon a web server and you make
亚马逊Web服务器和 你做
transactions you request something you
交易你要求你的东西
provide information and it gives you
提供信息，它给你
back pretty pictures of things you might
事情回到漂亮的图片，你可能
want to buy it acknowledges your credit
想购买它承认你的 信用
card transactions those are all very
卡交易这些都是非常
classic client-server types of
传统的客户端-服务器类型
interactions you as the client Amazon is
交互您作为客户端亚马逊
the server another interesting example
服务器的另一个有趣的例子
is a telephone so if you think about it
是一个电话，所以如果你仔细想想
a telephone is both a client and a
电话是一个客户端和一个
server in that when I'm making a placing
在服务器时，我正在做一个配售
a call to somebody else I'm the client
给某人打电话否则 我是客户端
and that person's phone is the server
而他的手机是服务器
right
对
it's sitting there waiting for calls to
它坐在那里等待 来电
come in and when that call comes in it
进来，当电话打进来，它
makes a connection we talk over the
让我们谈论过的连接
phone and then I hang up either side
电话， 然后我挂上两侧
hangs up so there's a lot of instances
挂断所以有很多实例
out there of some variation of client
在那里客户端的一些变化
and server and it's a much richer idea
和服务器，这是一个更丰富的想法
in that you can often switch back and
在你经常可以任意切换
forth the roles of those two parties but
这两个政党提出的作用，但
it's a pretty universal and a ubiquitous
这是一个相当 普遍的，无处不在
way of thinking about how to set up a
想着如何 设置 的方式
network system so in general then the
网络系统中一般如此， 则
idea is that there's a working the
想法是，有一个工作
client is making some requests to the
客户端做一些请求到
server the server does something locally
服务器的服务器做本地的东西
to deal with it it receives it gets
对付它接收到它得到
information that retrieves from its
从检索其信息
database the things you might want to
数据库中的东西，你可能 要
buy and then it sends back information
买， 然后将其发 回的信息
saying nicely formatted
他说很好地格式化
Paige with all kinds of shopping
佩奇有各类购物
suggestions and then the client decides
建议，然后客户决定
what to do next so from a hardware
从硬件下一步，这样做什么
perspective the interface to a between
透视之间的界面到
the network and your computer is called
网络和计算机被称为
the NIC or network interface card even
网卡或网络接口卡连
though it's not always on a card and we
虽然它并不总是一个卡，我们在
really won't talk about hardware at all
真的不会谈论硬件在所有
but what's most interesting from it is
但什么是最有趣的是
that it looks to your computer like an
它看起来到您的计算机就像一个
i/o device and in fact the UNIX of API
I / O设备和实际上API的 UNIX
for dealing with networks makes it look
用于处理 网络，使它看起来
like a file so in particular just as a
就像一个文件，以便在特定就像
disc sits off of a bus and you write
盘坐在离公共汽车和你写的
data to a disk or you read it from a
数据到磁盘或您从阅读
disk similarly it the network sits off
磁盘类似它的网络位于关
of a similar bus and when you want to
类似的公交车，当你想
send a message you actually do it by
发送一条消息，你真正做到这一点的
writing to a sort of virtual file that's
写一种虚拟的文件 ， 它是
called the network and if you want when
所谓的网络，如果你想在
you're receiving data you do it by
您收到的数据，你做的
reading and so just as several weeks ago
看书等，就像几周前
I gave the lecture on Io
我给演讲 木卫一
it turns out that it's extremely
事实证明，这是非常
relevant to network programming and
有关网络编程和
that's the basic model that that was
这是最基本的模型，这是
created by the early developers of the
通过对早期的开发人员创建
sort of standard UNIX
排序标准的UNIX
and now that carried over not just to
而现在结转 不仅仅是
UNIX but it's the same model for Windows
UNIX但它的 Windows 的同一 型号
and other operating systems so and now
和其他操作系统那么现在
let's just talk a little about what
让我们只谈了一点什么
computer networking means the idea of a
计算机网络手段的想法
network is it's a collection of systems
网络是它的系统集合
that are referred to as hosts that are
被称为作为主机
able to communicate with each other over
能够彼此 在 沟通
some kind of communication fabric let's
某种通信面料让我们
call it communication system and they're
称之为通信系统 和他们
sort of partitioned into mostly referred
排序分成大多简称
to as lands or local area networks that
为土地或本地区域网络
you establish within a small region and
你一个小的区域内建立
then a wide area network we
那么广域网我们
would be over something the size of a
将在东西 的大小
city or perhaps more and over a
城市或者更并在
Enterprise such as CMU it's a very
企业如CMU这是一个非常
complex set of for example there's
一套复杂的例如 有
wireless base stations that right in
无线基站的是在权
this room that you're interacting with
这个房间你与互动
when you're using a wireless system or
当您使用的是无线系统或
your your phone and then there's a whole
你的手机，然后有一个整体
networking infrastructure within the
内的网络基础设施
university that then goes to some
大学那然后去 一些
commercial providers AT&T in particular
商业提供商AT＆T特别
that give it access to the the
这给它进入的
commercial internet and then there's
商业互联网，然后有
another set of network connections
另一组 网络 连接 的
hosted by the supercomputing Center that
由超级计算中心托管了
give you access to what's called
给你什么叫做访问
Internet 2 which is the resource that's
互联网 2这是这就是资源
used for communicating among
用于 之间 通信
universities so underneath you know when
大学所以下面你知道什么时候
you're doing your networking stuff
你做你的网络 的东西
there's this amazingly complex
有这个太复杂了
combination of things going on the idea
事会的想法组合
of an Internet is supposed is refers to
的互联网应该是指
the idea the general idea of a network
这个想法在 网络 的总体思路
of networks taking for example the local
网络采取例如本地的
area network that this base station
区域网络 ，该基站
provides and connecting it up to other
提供和它连接到其他
networks on campus and across the world
在校园和整个世界网络
and when we refer to the capital I
当 我们指的是我的资本
internet that refers to the one instance
互联网是指一个实例
the the most significant instance of an
一个企业的最显著实例
Internet
互联网
so lowercase I means the sort of general
所以我小写字母表示的那种一般
idea of creating a network of networks
创建 网络 的网络的 想法
uppercase I is the specific example that
大写 I是具体示例
we all know and use all the time that's
我们都知道，并使用所有 的 时间
organized by a certain set of principles
由一组特定的原则组织
that uses a particularly set of
使用一个特别设置的
protocols and so forth and of course we
协议等等当然，我们和
tend to just talk the internet and most
往往只讲互联网最
people know that what that really
人们知道这是什么真正
implies is the sort of existing network
意味着是那种现有网络
structure that there is and that's good
结构有这很好
enough first through the purpose of this
够首先通过这样做的目的
course we're not going to talk much
当然，我们不打算 多谈
about other possible designs one might
关于其他可能的设计之一可能
have for a network so most of the low
有一个网络，使大部分低
level networking is supported by
级网络由支持
something called Ethernet and the term
一些所谓的以太网和术语
Ethernet actually has evolved tremendous
以太网实际上已演变巨大
over time so that it's almost more like
随着时间的推移， 这样它几乎 更像
a brand name that it is a specific
一个品牌名称， 它是一个 特定的
technology and the version you're
技术和 你 的版本
familiar with the wired version of it
熟悉它的有线版本
you have a wire to some sort of a box
你有丝某种一盒
like that you plug the your ethernet
就像你插上以太网
jacks into and historically those were
插孔成和历史那些是
called hubs and the idea of a hub was it
称为集线器和轮毂的想法 是它
was just a repeater that whatever came
只是， 无论来了一个中继器
into it from one computer it would
把它从一台计算机它会
broadcast to all the connected machines
广播到所有连接的机器
and so you only want to do this for
所以你只 需要做到这一点的
maybe a a dozen or so machines that it's
也许AA十几台左右的机器，它的
like a party-line they're all hearing
像党的路线他们都讯
what everybody else is saying and in
别人都在说和
fact the original first version the
其实原来的第一个版本
ethernet did that by everyone
以太网这样做，每个人都
interacting over a single cable carrying
过 一根电缆承载 交互
essentially radio sweet signals and
本质上无线电信号的甜蜜和
similarly when you're in this room using
同样，当你在这个房间是用
a wireless internet the wireless
无线互联网的无线
internet is sort of like a hub and that
互联网是有点像一个枢纽和
all the packets that you're sending all
所有你要发送的所有数据包
across the room they're all sort of
在房间里，他们都是那种
making use of the same radio frequencies
利用相同的 无线电频率 的
the same communication channel and
相同的通信信道和
there's a protocol for how they detect
还有他们如何检测协议
when two messages get set at the same
当两个消息能设置在同一
time and therefore interfere with each
时间，因此与每个干扰
other so that can only sort of scale up
其它这样 方能类 的扩展
to maybe at most a hundred different
对可能最多 一百个不同
hosts communicating because they're all
主机通信，因为它们都是
sharing a single communication channel
共享单个通信信道
now in the wired world what's evolved is
现在在有线 世界上发生了什么是发展
usually when you buy a box or you get
通常，当你买一箱或你
one from your cable company with all
一个从 有线电视公司 全体
those ports in it it's actually called a
那些它它实际上叫做端口
router or sometimes a switch in that it
路由器或有时在它的开关
it doesn't broadcast to everyone it
它不播报给大家它
selectively tries to guess is this
选择性地试图猜测这是
particular message bound for this
结合对于该特定消息
particular host and only send to that
特定主机，只发送到
one and as you know you can take these
一个如你所知，你可以把这些
and wire up I think about up to six
并线了 ，我想最多六个
levels deep in and hops and basically
深层次的和啤酒花和基本
create a net
创建一个网
work of wired connections and they'll
有线连接的工作，他们会
all get from one to the other somehow
从一个全部搞定其他莫名其妙
and then after that it gets more
再之后，它变得更
complicated you can add more
纷繁复杂，你可以添加更多
sophisticated types of switching on top
复杂类型的顶部开关
of it but so the general idea of even an
的，但这样 的甚至是 一般的想法
Ethernet is actually a fairly complex
以太网实际上是一个相当复杂的
thing but it's some sort of conceptual
的事情，但它是某种概念
level we can just think of it as a bunch
水平，我们可以只把它看作是一堆
of hosts that can talk directly to one
主机可以直接跟 一个
another and then an internet then refers
另外，然后互联网则是指
to the idea of taking those local area
要采取这些局部区域的想法
networks and connecting them together
网络并将其连接在一起
via routers and routers obey a
经由路由器和路由器服从
particular protocol based on the address
基于地址特定协议
that you're trying to send data to and
您正在尝试将 数据发送到与
and so what you end up with conceptually
所以你最终与概念
is a whole bunch of hosts spread
在主机的一大堆蔓延
potentially all across the world and
可能所有在世界各地和
then some magical system of routers that
然后路由器的一些神奇的系统，
will get a message from one place to the
从一个地方到得到一个消息
other based on a mode of addressing
其他基于寻址的一个模式
where there's some known address of the
那里的 的 一些已知地址
hosts that you're trying to send to and
您正在尝试 发送 给 主机 和
it will hop through multiple routers to
它会通过多个路由器跳
get from one place to the other and
从一个地方到另一个 ，
that's true whether it's on campus
这是真的不管是在校园
or whether it's hopping all the way
还是它的跳跃一路
around the world and so again there's
在世界各地，因此再次有
this huge body of information to
这个庞大的信息体
knowledge about how that routing works
有关如何，即路由工作知识
and how its reliable and all that but
如何以其可靠的和所有的，但
we're going to just assume that somebody
我们将只是假设某人
else's figured that out and our job as
他人享有想通了这一点 ，我们的工作为
programmers is just to be able to
程序员只是为了能够
communicate from one host to another
从一个主机到另一个通信
and so how could you design a system
所以你怎么能设计 一个系统
where all these diverse systems made by
所有这些不同的系统所作
computers made by different
通过不同的国产机
manufacturers operating under different
厂家根据不同的操作
countries with different
与不同国家
telecommunications bodies governing
电信管理机构
bodies and so forth how can they all
机构等等怎么能都
work with each other and the requirement
彼此 和工作要求
is you have to have a protocol you have
是你必须有你有一个协议
to have some common set of conventions
有一些共同的约定的
for what messages look like how they get
什么消息看起来像他们怎么弄
sent what happens if one of them doesn't
发送如果其中一人没有发生什么
make it how do you recover from that and
让你如何从恢复和
so forth and so what does the protocol
等等等什么呢协议
include well it has to include some way
包括好它必须包括一些方法
of naming things so that if I want to
事物命名的，这样，如果我想
send to some host I have some way of
发送到某些 主机我有一些方法
designating who that host is and then
指定该主机 是 谁 ，然后
there's the routing system has to have
还有的路由系统必须 有
some reliable way of getting my data to
让我的数据的一些可靠的方法
that named host and that's the delivery
名为主机 ，这就是交付
mechanism and that's usually done and
机制 而这通常 做 ，
one of the things that we now accept is
那我们现在接受的事情之一是
as universal but it really wasn't when
作为通用的，但真不是时候
it first came out was idea of you take
它首先出来的是你把想法
all your data and you divide it into
所有的数据 ，你把它分成
packets and packets are typically about
分组和分组通常约
a thousand to two thousand bytes and so
一千到两千个字节 等
if you have a longer message it chops it
如果你有一个较长的消息，它扒了它
up into individual packets and sends it
成单独的数据包，并将其发送
across and all the communication occurs
横跨所有的通信发生
in a packet level that's different than
在数据包级别比不同
the historic phone system was a
历史悠久的电话系统是一个
connection based system meaning that if
基于连接的系统，这意味着 ，如果
I was calling somebody there is a
我打电话人是有
dedicated wire set of wires maintained
专用线组导线保持
by the phone company that would be
由电话公司，这将是
reserved and locked down for our own use
保留并锁定为我所用
during the entire duration of that phone
该手机的整个持续过程
call
呼叫
so to get then from one host say A to B
因此要获得那么从一台主机说A到B
what happens is we want to send a packet
发生的事情是我们要发送一个数据包
and that packet will contain some amount
而包将包含一定量
of data and the idea of packet
数据和数据包的想法
communication then is you put little
那么沟通是你把小
headers on that contains to the routing
对报头包含路由
information the equivalent of what you'd
信息相当于你会
see on the front of an envelope of a
看到上的 信封的前
letter perhaps and so and at different
信也许等，并在不同的
points in the way they'll have different
在他们将 有不同 的方式分
numbers of headers and different
头和不同数量
protocols or formats for what those
协议或格式什么的
headers look like so in particular
标题，看起来像这样特别
within I wanted to send a message you
内我 想送 你 一个消息
know I'll do that and then the software
知道我会做到这一点，那么软件
that runs on my machine that handles
运行我的机器上处理
this will put a header in front of that
这将会把一个头前面那个
that describes the internet routing and
描述Internet路由和
then it will tack a header in front of
然后，将在前面的钉的头部
that that talks about the local area
这是谈到了局域
network routing that gets used so that's
这被使用 ，这样的 网络路由
what's referred to as the a P hat H the
什么是简称为P帽子小时
packet header for the Internet Protocol
分组报头的 因特网协议
and f h1 the frame header for this
和f H1为这个帧头
particular message being sent within
特定消息被发送内
this local network and then the network
这个本地网络 ，然后在网络
interface card or the adapter here is
接口卡或这里的适配器
then responsible for putting that out
然后负责演出 了
over this local communication of
在这种本地通信
capability and then that gets received
能力，那么被接受
at the other end by the network adapter
在由网络适配器 的 另一端
at the receivers direction it will put
在接收器的方向就会把
up its own frame header on it to pass it
起来就可以了它自己的帧报头将它传递
in and that then gets tripped off so
在那然后被绊倒关闭，因此
that all hosts B C's is the data that
所有 主机 B C的是数据
gets sent but this idea of putting
被发送，但这种想法当头
headers in front and at the time sort of
在前面，并在排序时头
what they call encapsulation that I'll
他们所谓的封装， 我会
take this big packet and I'll just tack
借此大包，我会只是钉
some more information on top to the
在上面的一些详细信息
front of it
它的前面
header information and I'll send through
报头信息，我会通过发送
the rest of it just
它 的其余部分 只是
as a set of bytes
作为一组的字节
so the internet that we know and love
所以我们知道互联网和 爱
the capital I internet then has a
那么资本我网上有
particular set of protocols that are
组特定的协议
you've probably heard the terms one is
你 可能听说过的条款之一是
called the IP the Internet Protocol
称为 IP 互联网 协议
which is the one that defines ideas
这是定义思想的一个
about how do you get how do you name
关于你如何让你怎么命名
hosts on the Internet and how do you
Internet 上的主机，你如何
send packets and they're referred to
发送数据包，他们称
sometimes as datagrams meaning that a
有时数据报含义一个
packet is just a single entity that gets
包仅仅是得到一个单一实体
sent from point A to point B and the
从点A发送到B点和
underlying IP doesn't guarantee delivery
底层的IP并不能 保证交货
so it's based on what they call best
所以它的基础上，他们叫什么最好
effort of communication meaning that at
通信意义的努力，在
each step along the way if for example
沿着如果例如每一步
things are good then it will just send
东西是好那么它将只发送
this packet along if there's too much
沿着如果有太多这样的分组
congestion there's been a you know
拥堵 还有的是一个你知道
somebody's turned on their microwave
有人在开启他们的微波
oven and it's set up some radiofrequency
烤箱和它的成立一些射频
interface interference then at the IP
在IP接口的干扰，然后
level it just drops that packet and says
水平，它 只是丢弃该数据包，并说
whoops I screwed up sorry it doesn't
哎呦我搞砸了抱歉， 它不
even say sorry it just does it silently
甚至说对不起它只是 它默默地
and then you can as a programmer make
然后你就可以作为一个程序员做
use of that very low level so normally
使用非常低的水平 ， 这样正常
as a programmer you don't really want to
作为一个程序员 ，你 真的不想要
program at that level because you'll
计划在这一 水平，因为你
send packets and they will get there but
发送数据包的时候，就会到达那里，但
you can if you want to and it's called
你可以，如果你想 ，这就是所谓
UDP a protocol it's just a small
UDP协议，它只是一个小
software layer over IP and there's some
在IP软件层，并有一些
applications that you'll see for example
你会看到 示例应用
in the computer game world where you
在电脑游戏世界里，你
want to send information really fast and
要发送的信息实在是快，
if some information gets dropped it's
如果某些信息就会丢失它的
not a big deal that people actually
没什么大不了的， 人们的实际
program at that level we won't really
在该级别的程序，我们不会真的
talk about that the more common protocol
谈论比较常见的协议
that gets used and carries 99% of
该被使用和携带的99％
Internet traffic is what's called TCP or
互联网流量是一般所谓的TCP或
transmission control protocol and that
传输控制协议和
provides the reliable the the equivalent
提供了可靠的 等效
of telephone connections that I can
电话 联系，我可以
reliably send data from point A to point
可靠地从点A 的数据发送 到 指向
B
乙
as many vices are like it's guaranteed
因为种种罪恶都喜欢它保证
delivery it's sometimes fast and
交付它有时快
sometimes not but it's there and it's
有时没有，但它的存在和它的
built on top of the IP of this Datagram
建立在这个数据包的IP 之上
meaning that it has to take whatever
这意味着它 必须 采取一切
you're sending and slice it up into the
你发送和切片它分成 了
single packets if one of them doesn't
单一的数据包，如果其中一人不
get sent it will resend it until it gets
被发送，直到它得到它会重新发送它
there they have to deal with the fact
在那里，他们不得不 面对的事实
that packets can travel different paths
数据包可以前往不同的路径
and one can get ahead of the other in
人们可以得到其他的超前
transmission and so it has to reorder
传输等它重新排序
them in the correct sequence and so
他们以 正确的顺序 等
there's a lot of stuff under it but
有下了很多的东西，但
we'll just assume that it kind of works
我们姑且认为它种作品
and so you can just rely think about it
所以你可以仅仅依靠想想
is I have a stream connection I can send
是我有一个流连接，我可以送
from A to B and B can send a stream of
从A到B和B可以发送的流
data back to me and we're all happy and
数据反馈给我 ，我们都高兴 ，
so that's the version that looks like
所以这是一个外形类似版本
file i/o I just keep writing to a file
文件I / O我只是不停地写文件
and it's sending packets over the
并且它在发送数据包
network to the other end and then the
网络到另一 端，然后将
other side can be sending stuff to me
对方可以发送的东西 给我
and I'm just reading it and I'm just
而我 只是读它 ，我只是
reading bytes of data not worrying about
阅读 不担心 数据的字节
how that got broken up into individual
这是怎么分解 为单独的
packets and so that's referred to as the
包和所以这被称为
sockets interface and you'll hear the
套接字 接口，你会听到
term socket programming and that's
长期socket编程，这就是
exactly what we're talking about
我们在谈论什么
and so from a sort of software system
所以从某种软件系统
than software hardware system then the
比软件硬件系统则
client and the server are both
客户端和服务器都
implemented as application programs at
作为应用程序，来实现
the respective endpoints on their hosts
对 寄主的各个端点
and they make use of of software and
和他们做的软件使用，
libraries that run some combination of
运行的某种组合库
the user level and at the kernel level
用户级别 和 内核 级别
and therefore I have access to direct
因此 ， 我有机会直接
resources and so I is a program or an
资源，所以我是一个程序或
application programmer then make use of
然后应用程序员利用
this software API that lets me do socket
这个软件的API，允许我做窝
programming and it's based on gives
编程和它是基于给
directly supports tcp/ip
直接支持TCP / IP
so first of all we're going to talk most
所以首先我们要谈的最多
of the time about what called ipv4 a
关于什么叫IPv4中的时间
version 4 which is the one that's been
第4版这 是一直 的一个
running for since the 1980s I think
运行自1980年代以来，我认为
early 1980s and is the standard and
80年代初，是标准
we'll talk very only mentioned very
我们聊得很只有 极提到
briefly the idea of what's called ipv6
什么叫做IPv6的简单想法
which is sort of a next-generation
这是排序的 下一代 的
version so the idea of a ipv4 and this
版本所以的IPv4的想法，这
is now we're talking about IP and and
现在我们谈论的IP和和
this is true of TCP as well is that an
这是TCP也是如此是 的
address is actually just 32 bits but
地址实际上只是32位，但
it's usually expressed in what they call
它通常在他们所谓的表达
dotted decimal form and you've seen
点分十进制形式，你见过
these addresses before that it's four
它的前四这些地址
decimal numbers and they can only range
十进制数和他们只能范围
between 0 and 255 because each one of
因为每一个 0和255之间
them is a single byte sorts of
它们是单字节各种各样的
information so we're used to writing
信息，以便我们已经习惯了书写
things in hex now in this course but
事情六角现在在这个过程中，但
we're going to write it as each byte is
我们打算把它写成 每个字节
written as a decimal digit and they're
写为十进制数，他们是
actually passed and stored in what's
实际上，并且存储在什么
called network byte order which is big
所谓的网络字节顺序是大
endian byte order and so we have to
尾数字节顺序，所以我们要
worry about the whole big endian versus
担心整个大端 与
good ole Indian thing when we're doing
当我们正在做老好人印度的东西
network programming and you can actually
网络编程实际上 ，你可以
learn a lot there's a whole of levels of
学到很多东西有一个整体的水平
how the different bytes mean but for
如何在不同的字节意味着但
example any IP address it starts with
例如任何IP地址 ，与开始
128 - is it CMU I think and then and so
128 -是CMU 我觉得再等等
essentially CMU owns that part of the IP
基本上CMU拥有IP的一部分
address space which if you think about
如果你 认为哪些地址空间
that approximately 2 to the 64th 2 to
有 大约2至第64个2至
the
该
no not to the 64th - to the 16th
无不是在 第64 -到 16
a different IP address is available for
不同的IP 地址可 用于
use by campus alma and as i mentioned
通过校园母校和我提到使用
there's a newer version called ipv6 that
有一个较新的版本称为IPv6 是
gives you a 128-bit addresses you can
为您提供了一个可以 128位地址
imagine actually that if you think about
其实可以想象，如果你想
how many nodes are there in the internet
在互联网上有多少节点 有
if a four byte address is only two to
如果一个四个字节的地址是唯一的两
the 32 so that's four billion and I
32，这样的四十亿，我
don't know about you but I have a lot of
不知道你，但我有很多的
different things that use IP I have a
使用IP不同的东西， 我有一个
phone I have two laptops I have a couple
手机我 有两个笔记本电脑我有一对夫妇
desktops so if all if every one of us
台式机，所以如果所有，如果我们每个人都
use multiple IP addresses then actually
使用多个IP地址，则实际
the world would be out of them right
世界会出 他们的 权
there's 7 billion people in the world
还有的七座十亿人的世界
not all of who may have access to the
不是 所有 的谁可以访问 到
Internet but a large fraction of them do
Internet，但 他们 中的很大一部分 做
and so there's a whole kind of crazy way
所以有一个整体的一种疯狂的方式
of dealing with the the multitude of
处理的众多的
possible IP addresses so the obvious
可能的IP地址，从而 明显
thing would be well let's just allocate
事情会得到很好的让我们只分配
a lot more addresses and jump what's to
更大量 的地址和跳什么对
skip 64 bits and go right to 128 and
跳过64位，向右走为128，
that's the idea behind ipv6 but quite
这背后的IPv6，但蛮有想法
honestly this has been one of those
老实说，这一直 是 其中的一个
technologies that's been out there for
这一直是那里的技术
over 15 years and still has a very low
超过15年，仍然具有非常低的
level of adoption so it's it's still a
采用的水平，从而它的它仍然是一个
future technology people have basically
未来技术的人有基本
figured out all these crazy schemes to
想通了这些疯狂的计划，
make use of just stick within the four
利用只是坚持 四个内
byte limit
字节的限制
um
UM
okay so let's start talking the program
好了，让我们开始谈话 节目
the sort of programmer perspective on
那种程序员的角度对
this and this is one area where you'll
这一点，这 是一个领域， 你会
wish you weren't programming in C but
希望你不是在C编程，但是
you are so there's a lot of really
你这么有很多的真
crusty stuff and it was all developed
硬壳 的东西，这是所有 开发
most of the software protocols were
大多数的软件协议是
conceived before he even was what it is
怀孕之前， 他 甚至是它是什么
today
今天
so like the Kernighan and Ritchie book
所以像Kernighan和Ritchie书
you have is called the second edition
你已经被称为第二版
and it's based on what was called ANSI C
它是基于什么被 称为ANSI C
or ISO C but these all date before that
或ISO C但在此之前，这些所有的日期
they date back to the original Kernighan
它们可以追溯到 原来的Kernighan的
and Ritchie so for example void star did
和Ritchie 因此， 例如无效明星做
not exist in that era and so you use
在那个时代不存在的，所以你用
care stars a generic pointer and so
关心明星通用指针等
there's just a lot of stuff in this
但只是很多 东西在这
programming interface where you go wow
编程接口你走到哪里哇
that is really crusty and the truth is
这确实是 一个易怒的，事实是
yes you're right
你是对的
so in particularly there's a lot of
所以特别有很多的
different structures that are defined
中定义 的不同的结构
and one of them is called an in adder
其中一个被称为加法器
which means internet address and it's
这意味着互联网地址和它的
just defined to be a 32-bit unsigned
只是定义为一个32位无符号
number and in general as I mentioned
数量和一般正如我所提到
there the so called network byte order
还有 所谓 的 网络字节顺序
whoever designed the original protocols
谁设计了最初的协议
was a fan of big endian addressing and
在 大端 的粉丝 寻址和
so that's what it is even though
所以这是它 是什么，即使
actually most of the machines that are
实际上大部分是机器
out there in this world are little
赫然出现 在这个 世界上是 很少
endian and so there's a set of standard
endian和所以有一组 标准的
library functions that you use to
您使用库函数
convert between network order and host
网络秩序和主机之间进行转换
order and the idea of it is now if I run
订购和现在它的想法是，如果我跑
my software on a little Indian or a big
我的一个小 印度或大 的软件
endian machine these functions will do
endian机器这些功能将做
the right thing so if I just use these
正确的事情，所以如果我只是用这些
standard libraries then I don't have to
标准库那我就不必
worry about porting it every time I
担心将它移植每次我
change the word or during the machine
更改机器中的单词或
one of the things you'll notice here is
在这里 ，你会注意到的事情之一是
there is no function to convert 64-bit
没有功能转换64位
data between a network order and host
网络命令和主机之间的数据
order so I don't know what people do
为了让我不知道是什么人做
when I do it I just write my own set my
当我这样做，我只是写我自己的一套我
own function
自己的功能
to do it or I don't because I know my
这样做，否则我不会，因为我知道我的
other end is a little endian machine
另一端为小端机
so anyways these are already some
所以反正这些都是已经有一些
functions you'll start seeing for that
功能，你会开始看到该
look like network conversion software
像网络转换软件
[Music]
[音乐]
and as I mentioned the addresses are
正如我所提到的地址是
written in a dotted decimal form and
写在一个点分十进制形式
it's also big endian so if I were to
它也是大端所以如果 我是
write in hex 128 is of course 8 0 so
以十六进制 128 写入 当然 8 0， 以便
that's the most significant byte of the
这是的最显著字节
IP address and then there is a set of
IP地址 ，然后有一组
functions API calls you can use to
功能API调用，您可以用它来
convert between this dotted decimal
这 点分十进制 之间的转换
format and the actual just a 32-bit
格式和实际只是一个32位
unsigned int and actually it used to be
unsigned int类型，实际上它使用的是
there is you might see some older
有可能 会看到一些旧的
presentations where they use different
在那里，他们用不同的表现形式
names for this but the most recent
这可是最近的 名字
version API calls this the the
版本API称此为中
presentation version the dotted decimal
演示版的点分十进制
they referred to it as a presentation
他们把 它称为一个演示
then you can look up the and it's in the
那么你可以看一下，它是在
book to what the calls to these look
书要什么给 这些 来电 看
like but you probably don't or very
喜欢但你可能没有或极
seldom when you're thinking about I want
很少，当你想着 我 要
to go to Google you don't think about
去谷歌，你 不想想
what its IP address is you just go to wo
什么IP 地址是你只是去WO
comm and for everything you do you refer
COMM 和 你 所做的 一切 你参考
to it by this it would have referred
它通过这一点，就不得不提到
called Internet domain names which is a
所谓的互联网域名是一个
hierarchical naming system where as you
分层命名系统 中， 你
know there's dot edu is for educational
知道有圆点 EDU是为教育
institutions com is for commercial net
机构com是商业网
is general networking of many countries
是许多国家的通用网络
have their own suffix so you know dot de
有自己的后缀，所以你知道点解
is for Germany and so forth and so those
是德国等等等等这些
are called the first level domain names
被称为第一级域名
and then there's a hierarchal naming
然后有一个 层次命名
structure under that and uh
根据该结构和呃
there's actually an interesting question
实际上，有一个有趣的问题
of okay how do I then map from those
好吗 我 怎么 那么从这些地图
hierarchical names those domain names
层次名称的域名
into this dotted decimal or the 32 bit
到该点分十进制或32位
IP address and the job of that is by a
IP地址和该作业是由
very large distributed system called the
非常大的分布式系统称为
DNS the domain name system where the
DNS域名系统，其中
only sort of centrally managed part of
只有那种集中管理的一部分
it is at the top level so for each of
它是在顶部电平，以便为每个
these first level domain names there's
这些一级域名有
there's a collection a very large
有一个收集非常大
collection of machines that keep track
机器的集合，跟踪
of all the all the IP addresses that map
所有的一切映射 IP地址
to one of those first level domain names
那些一级域名之一
and then for example CMU maintains its
再例如CMU保持其
own naming Authority so anything that
自己的命名管理局所以任何
says something
说了什么
CMU edu there's local DNS servers within
CMU EDU有内部的本地DNS服务器
CMU that are picking apart okay where
CMU被采摘开好地方
should you know if I say CS CMU edu what
你应该知道，如果我说CS CMU EDU什么
would be the the IP address for that
将是该 IP地址
well and it's actually pretty
好，它实际上是相当
interesting how this is managed because
有趣的 ，这是如何管理的，因为
it's all it's totally decentralized
这一切这是完全分散
there's a whole set of protocols that
有一个一整套 的协议是
govern how naming is done so but
执政的命名是如何这样做，但
conceptually we can think of it as just
概念，我们可以把它看成只是
this big database that gives me a
这个大的数据库，给了我一个
mapping where I can give a domain name
映射，其中我可以给一个域名
and it will get back to me a one or more
它会回来给我一个或多个
IP addresses I can give an IP address
IP地址我可以给一个IP 地址
and it will come back with one or more
它 会回来与一个或多个
domain names
域名
and so there's actually an application
所以有实际上是一个应用程序
you can run on most machines called
你可以在 大多数机器 上运行 叫
nslookup and there's another one called
NSLOOKUP并有另外一个叫
dig that you can use to find basically
挖，你可以用它来找到基本
probe the DNS and find in either
探测DNS和发现无论是
direction you can look at the given a
方向，你可以看看给予
domain name you can find its IP address
域名你可以找到它的IP地址
given an IP address you can find its
给出 你可以找到 一个IP地址， 其
domain name and we also I'll show you
域名，我们也我会告诉你
some code that just as an example of how
一些代码，就像 如何 为例
you do the programming I'll just show
你做的节目，我会只显示
that momentarily called hostname so just
那瞬间名为hostname所以才
some examples
一些例子
you know if I look up some address like
你知道，如果我看到一些像地址
the the website for the computer science
该网站的计算机科学
school computer science using nslookup
使用nslookup学校计算机科学
it comes back can people see this okay
它回来 的人 可以 看到这个 行不行
you want it bigger okay so this is what
你希望它更大的好，所以这是什么
NSF looks like and this stuff here just
NSF 的样子，只是这东西在这里
tells you you know who where was the
告诉你，你知道是谁在那里有
actual directory entry in the which DNS
在其DNS实际的目录项
server actually gave this information
服务器实际上给这个信息
back and it says that WCAG mu is
回来了 ，它说WCAG万亩
actually a synonym for a weirder one
其实对于一个怪异的代名词
called W web - lb servcie SC mu dot edu
所谓Z资源-磅servcie SC亩埃杜点
and its IP address is 128 - like you'd
并且其IP地址为128 -像你
expect
期望
- 1713 and of course that works not just
- 1713当然那只是工作不
at CMU but I can you know go ask about
在CMU但我可以知道去问问
what Stanford is up to and it will come
什么斯坦福达，它会来
back and it's IP addresses of something
回来了， 它的一些IP地址
170 1.64 and that's been managed by that
170 1.64 和一个已经由管理
and you'll see again it I asked for WCS
你会再次看到它，我问WCS
at Stanford you said well the real name
在斯坦福你说得好的真实姓名
of that is CS dot stanford.edu and this
那 是CS点stanford.edu这
actually is a point that the the mapping
实际上是一个点，该映射
between domain names and Internet
域名和互联网之间
addresses is not one-to-one you can have
地址是不是一个对一个，你可以有
multiple domain names that refer to the
这指的是多个域名
same Internet address but you can also
同互联网地址，但 你也可以
have multiple internet addresses
拥有多个互联网地址
excuse me
打扰一下
that's weird
这很奇怪
oh so like twitter.com when I ask for it
哦，所以像twitter.com时，我问它
it comes back with four different
它回来了四种 不同
addresses and if I do the exact same
地址，如果我做同样的
thing again mmm Kimba yeah you see it
事情再次MMM Kimba是啊，你看它
came back with the same no not even the
回来后用相同 甚至 无不是
same addresses it came back for example
同一地址它回来了，例如
here the one that ends with dot six that
在这里，与点6结束一个
wasn't in that first twist so it came
并没有在第一扭转所以来到
back with a slightly different set of
背部 采用了略有不同 的
addresses and a somewhat different
地址 和一个有些不同
orders and the idea of that is that it
订单和的 这个 想法 是，它
actually has multiple servers so when I
实际上有多个服务器，所以当我
send to twitter.com or Google or any of
发送到twitter.com或谷歌或任何的
these major servers there's not just one
这些主要的服务器有不 只是一个
place in the internet that's handling
放置在在处理互联网
everybody's Google traffic these
每个人的谷歌流量这些
thousands of places spread around the
数以千计的地方周围蔓延
world and the way they get you there is
世界 和方式，他们让你有
by playing tricks with the DNS that
通过玩弄花招与DNS是
Google is constantly sending updates to
谷歌在不断 的更新发送到
the it maintains its own DNS servers so
在保持其自己的DNS服务器，以便
it's constantly changing them and it
它是不断变化的他们， 这
will actually give you different
实际上会给你不同
addresses depending on where in the
地址不同的地方在
world you located as well to try and
世界而言，你所在以及尝试
provide a server that's sort of
提供的排序服务器
reasonably close to you geographically
合理地接近你地理
so there's all just all kinds of tricks
所以一切都只是各种花样
that happen through DNS that is part of
这种情况发生通过DNS是的一部分
the way they can sort of manage this
他们可以排序的管理这种方式
huge set of addresses and then there's
巨大的地址集，然后有
some other domain names that don't have
没有一些其他域名
any IP address that they're somewhere in
他们是在某处任何IP地址
the hierarchy that hierarchical naming
该层次结构层次命名
system but they're not actually
系统，但他们不是真的
referring to a particular host so it's a
指的是一个特定的主机 所以这是一个
Multi multi mapping then the the API so
多的多的映射，则该API，以便
reflects that
反映
so this is just going what I told you
所以这只是要我告诉你
they sometimes one-to-one sometimes many
他们有时一到一个有时多
domain names refer to the same address
域名指向同一个地址
sometimes of one name maps to multiple
有时候一个人的名字映射到多个
addresses that change over time and then
随着时间的推移 ，然后 更改地址
there's some where it's a valid name but
有一些地方是一个有效的名称，但
it doesn't have an IP address it doesn't
它没有IP地址它不
have a host associated with a question
有一台主机与一个问题有关
the other is like given to a server for
另 一种是 像给 一个服务器
example let's say I create them how does
例如，让我们说，我创建 他们怎么做
that hold a number generator oh how do I
持有一个号码 发生器 哦， 我该怎么办
get how do you get your own IP address
让你如何让自己的IP地址
well all you have to beg borrow or you
以及你所求借，或者你
have to either borrow or buy them so for
必须要么借用或购买他们所以
example at CMU there is some number of
例如在CMU 存在的一些数
what they call statically allocated IP
他们所谓的静态分配IP
addresses where it's just fixed assigned
它只是固定分配的地址
to that machine and you can register
那台机器，你可以 注册
form and request them through computing
形成，并请求他们通过计算
services but most you don't have that
服务，但大多数你没有说
most you get one that's I signed
最让你得到一个是我签
dynamically so there's a pool of
动态所以有池
addresses that you basically they call
解决了 你基本上 他们叫
them leasing that you are assigned with
他们租赁，你与分配
for a while and then but it could
一会儿，然后但它可能
possibly be reassigned to someone else
可能被重新分配给其他人
and that's part of the way it can manage
这就是它能够管理方式的一部分
the somewhat limited set of IP addresses
设定比较有限的IP地址
so the idea of like I said that the main
所以 喜欢的 想法， 我说，主
a way we'll think about it is in terms
我们会考虑 的一个办法 是在条款
of what's called TCP and it's this
什么叫做TCP和它的这个
connection-oriented protocol where I
面向连接的协议，其中 我
establish a connection from one one host
建立从一个一个 主机的连接
establishes a connection to another host
建立到 另一台主机的连接
and they they can communicate to each
和他们，他们可以给每个通信
other sending arbitrarily long streams
其他发送任意长的流
of bytes to each other and so the
字节彼此等等的
connection is then two hosts that can
然后，连接两台主机，可以
talk to each other and each of those
互相交谈每一类又
endpoints is referred to as a socket and
端点被称为一个插座和
so I can and a socket is both an IP
所以我可以和插座既是一个IP
address and what's called a port number
地址和什么叫做端口 号
so there's a 16 by 16 bit number for
所以有一个16×16位的数字
every connection that's referred to as
多数民众赞成简称 为每个连接
its port and the reason for that is just
它的端口和其中的原因 仅仅是
because I'm talking to a particular
因为我说的是一个特定的
machine that that machine can support
机器，这台机器可以支持
different services it can provide SSH
不同的服务可以提供SSH
connections it can provide FTP
连接可以提供FTP
connections it can host a mail server it
连接它可以承载一个邮件服务器，它
can host a web server so a particular
可以承载一个Web服务器，以便在特定
machine might have a multitude of
机器可能有多种
different services and so those are
不同的服务 等等这些都是
differentiated from each other with what
彼此有什么区别
are called port numbers and similarly
被称为端口号，同样
Isaac client might have connections to
艾萨克客户 可能需要连接
dozens of hosts going at any given time
数十家主机在任何给定的时间去
I'm cruising the web I'm you know doing
我游弋在网络我是你知道这样
all that different stuff and that's all
所有不同的东西 ，这一切
differentiated the client end that
区分客户端是
there's different ports associated with
有相关联的不同端口
your different programs that are running
你不同的程序正在运行
and so a port then is a 16-bit integer
各个端口然后是一个16位的 整数
that identifies which particular
标识哪些特定
endpoint is is being communicated with
端点被连通
it either the client side of the server
它在服务器的 客户端
side and typically at the client side
侧，并且通常在客户端侧
these are assigned dynamically and the
这些动态分配和
referred to as the ephemeral ports
称为临时端口
meaning they only are assigned for the
这意味着他们只被分配给
limited duration that you have a
你有一个有限的时间
connection with that that you're
与你是连接
maintaining that connection
保持该连接
and then there has to be some way if I'm
然后必须有一定的方式，如果我
going to contact and I want to know the
要联系，我想知道
DNS will tell me what the IP address is
DNS会告诉我的IP 地址是 什么
of say google.com but I have to know
都说google.com， 但我必须知道
that
那
am i communicating with its web service
我就是从它的Web服务通信
which is port 80 or HTTP secure socket
这是端口80 或HTTP安全套接字
is a different report number so which
是一个不同的报告数量，以便其
service I'm asking for and there's a
服务我所要求的，有一个
standard list what are called well-known
标准清单 所谓的知名
ports that are that I can contact at the
端口是， 我可以在接触
server end to get the particular service
服务器端，以获得特定服务
I'm looking for and those are assigned
我在寻找那些被分配
there's a big list of port assignments
有端口分配的大名单
and so the again that's part of the sort
所以再次这是排序的一部分
of a whole set of internet standards is
一整套的互联网标准是
the the identifiers for the different
该标识符的不同
ports what services those are and how
端口这些都是什么服务，以及如何
those particular protocols work
特别是那些工作协议
so when I have a connection then
所以当我有一个连接，然后
as I mentioned think of it as a
正如我所说的它看成是一个
connection then is a link between two
然后连接两者之间的链路
machines based on some known port
根据一些已知端口的机器
typically at the server end and a
通常在服务器端和一个
dynamically assigned or ephemeral port
动态分配的或短暂端口
assigned at the client in and I can
在客户指定的，我可以
refer to them that connection then is
指他们连接，然后是
identified by the combination of the
通过 的组合来标识
hosts at the two ends and the ports that
在两端主机和端口
they're using
他们使用
and in general then it's the job of the
和一般那么它 的 工作
colonel to differentiate the different
上校区分不同
connections that are coming into a
正在进入一个 连接
machine and figure out which software
机，并找出哪些软件
which process to wake up when a data you
唤醒哪个进程了，当你的数据
know when some data arrives from another
知道什么时候一些数据从另一个到达
machine in which actual program running
机械，在 实际的程序 运行
on that machine will make use of that
这台机器上会利用该
data and that's done by associating for
数据而这 通过关联的完成
each of the ports a particular process
每个端口 的特定过程的
executing program that's going to handle
执行这回事处理程序
those particular requests and it's
这些特殊的要求， 它的
totally possible for a client to be
完全 有可能为客户要
interacting with a single server over
单个服务器上进行交互
different ports but those are considered
不同的端口，但那些被认为是
to be different connections and and so
是不同的连接和等
they don't really interfere with each
他们并不真正井水不犯河水
other
其他
so that's what I mentioned is this is
所以这就是我提到的是，这是
what we refer to as sockets programming
我们所说的 socket编程什么
or the sockets interface and it was
或者套接字接口，它是
developed sort of as the internet was
发达的排序当互联网
evolving in the late 70s and early 80's
不断发展在70年代末和 80年代 初
so socket then as I said is certain
我这么说套接字，则是一定的
logically one end one of the two ends of
逻辑上一个端部 的两个端部中的 一个
a connection and from an application
从应用程序的连接，并
point of view you'll see it as a file
的角度来看，你会看到它作为一个文件
descriptor to the low-level file stuff
描述到低级别 文件的东西
that you've already seen that you can do
你已经看到 ，你可以做
reading and writing from um and and so
阅读和写作从UM 和等
that it's a sort of mental model that is
它是 一种心智模式是
provided by the socket interface but
通过套接字接口提供，但
it's a very different you know the
这是一个你知道的很不同
actual implementation of network when
实际执行 时， 网络的
you write to a socket it's firing up all
你写一个套接字 这一切都发射了
kinds of network stuff whereas you write
各种网络的东西，而你写
to a disk it's operating or disk
到磁盘它的操作或磁盘
controller so at the hardware level and
控制器，从而在硬件级和
even at the lower levels of software
即使在较低级别的软件
they're very different beasts but you as
他们是非常不同的东西，但你如
an application programmers see some
应用程序的程序员看到一些
commonality there
有共性
okay so let's jump right into the API
好了，所以不如让我们跳进API
and again this is a place where you
并再次，这是一个地方，你
you'll wish you were programming in a
你会希望你在一个被编程
language that had a type hierarchy but
语言有一个类型 层次，但
you aren't you're programming in C so
你是不是你在C语言进行编程，以便
there's a type there's a zillion
有一个类型有一个数不胜数
Struck's that you kind of have to get
施特鲁克的，你那种必须得到
familiar with but one is called a sock
熟悉不过 的一个被称为袜子
adder and basically it's just a sixteen
加法器，基本上它只是一个 十六
bytes worth of stuff where the the only
字节价值的东西，其中只有
thing that's special here is that the
这里的特别之处 是，
leading two bytes designate what type of
领先的两个字节指定什么类型 的
socket this is particularly be different
插座，这是特别是不同
whether it's a TCP socket an ipv6 socket
无论是TCP套接字IPv6套接字
a UDP socket and all those will have
UDP 套接字，所有这些将有
different numbers a different constant
不同数量的不同常数
in there that tells you which type of
在那里，告诉你哪种类型的
socket it is and then at the high level
插座是，然后 在较高水平
the sockets in a lot of the programs
在很多项目的插座
don't need to know you know which type
不需要知道你知道哪种类型
of connection this is they can just deal
这种连接是他们可以处理
with they basically call other software
与他们基本上 调用其他的软件
to deal with that
对付那
so that's why it's referred to as being
所以这就是为什么它被称为 是
family specific and then the socket
家庭具体然后插座
stuff isn't even necessarily referred to
东西甚至没有必要 提及
the internet the capital I under net and
互联网资本我下网，
so there's a more specific one called a
所以有一个更具体的一个叫做
socket or underscore in that is used for
插座或下划线在于用于
ipv4 sockets oh not ipv6 and so in
IPv4的插座 哦不支持IPv6， 因此在
particular it fills in fields one is
特别是它填补了领域之一
called the port which is I mentioned
叫这是我所提到的端口
it's 16 bits and then the IP address the
这是16位，然后IP地址
4 byte IP address both of which are in
4个字节的IP地址两者都在
even if you're running the software on a
即使你正在运行一个软件
x86 machine these should be in big
x86机器，这些 应该是 在 大
endian order I'll and you'll see that
尾序 我会和你会看到
this is what I mean that this is sort of
这就是我的意思是，这 是有点
a C's version of subtyping if you know
一个C版的子类型的，如果你知道
something like C++ or Java for you know
像C ++或Java的，你知道
a language with type inheritance that
与类型继承一种语言，
you can think of it as a sock adder in a
你可以把它作为一个袜子加法器
sort of a subclass of a sock adder it
那种 袜子的子类 的 加法器它
has more information it's compatible
有更多的信息，它是兼容
with but has more information than a
有但不是更多信息
socket and then there's another type of
插座，然后还有另一种类型的
for ipv6 has a different kind of struct
对IPv6 有着别样的结构
that they fill in for its information
他们填写其信息
and then they they Pat it out with 8
然后他们他们轻拍它具有 8个
bytes of zeros just because this
零字节就因为这个
particular protocol doesn't require the
特定的协议不要求
full 16 bytes
满16个字节
okay so this is sort of what it looks
好了，所以这是有点它看起来什么
like to operate a full-blown
喜欢操作盛放
client-server system from a programmers
从程序员的客户端 - 服务器系统
perspective and we're going to for the
角度，我们要为
rest of today and all of Thursday go
今天的休息和所有周四去
through all these steps and you as a
通过所有这些步骤 ，你作为一个
programmer are actually going to have to
程序员实际上将不得不
understand each of these steps what they
了解每一个步骤 他们
do what they mean and how to use them
做他们的意思，以及如何使用它们
the good news is there's some pretty
好消息是有一些相当
standard patterns here and so you can
这里的标准模式，所以你可以
often grab some existing code say out of
往往抓住一些现有的代码说出来的
the book to use that will make this not
书到用这将使这是不
as painful as it might look so but the
那么痛苦，因为它可能看起来如此，但
overall idea of this this picture then
这这幅画的总体思路，然后
is so I can't give you specifically
是这样，我不能给你明确
remote doesn't work on the the
遥控器 上不工作
right-hand side refers to the steps that
右手侧指的步骤
the server has to go through and the
服务器要经过和
left-hand side is what the client does
左边是客户做什么
so the upper right is what it takes to
所以右上方是什么需要
set up a server that is then a program
建立一个服务器，然后是一个程序
that's running there ready to receive
是的运行有准备 接收
connections from a client and perform
从客户端的连接，并执行
various services and so obviously before
各种服务和如此明显前
the client can do anything the server
客户端可以做任何事情的服务器
has to exist so that has to be the first
必须存在，这样 才能 有可能成为 第一
step in setting things up and then we
一步了，然后我们设置的东西
have to well fire for a client that will
有好火了客户端会
make use of this service and then
使用这项服务，然后
there'll be what's referred to as this
还会有什么被称为本
session meaning a kind of back and forth
会议 意味着 一种来回
communication between the client and
客户机之间的通信
server doing whatever they're going to
服务器做什么他们打算
do this is not specific to any
做到这一点并不针对任何
particular application and like I said
特定的应用程序就像我说的
it will involve you'll see Rio
它将涉及您会看到里约
underscore remember those who are
下划线记得那些谁是
reliable i/o functions we talked about
可靠的I / O功能，我们谈到了
as part of the UNIX i/o so it's a way to
作为 UNIX 的部分 I / O所以这是一个办法
read and write in a room and and handle
阅读和在一个房间里写，并处理
some of the quirks of low-level i/o but
一些低级的怪异的 I / O而
basically this is sending and receiving
基本上，这是发送和接收
messages over the Internet
在互联网上的消息
and then once that done typically then
再一次， 通常随后进行
the client will close its connection
客户端将关闭其连接
sort of equivalent of hanging up its
那种吊起来的相当于其
phone and say okay I'm done and then
电话，说好我做 ，然后
sometime later or maybe never depending
晚些时候或也许永远不会依赖
on what kind of web you know service
什么样的网站，你知道服务
this is if the the server wants to shut
这是如果 服务器要关闭
down it has its own collection of calls
倒也有其自己的呼叫集合
that it makes to stop that service so
它使停止 该服务，所以
anyways just to kind of give you the
反正只是 来 样给你
landscape of what this picture means
什么这张照片意味着 景观
so we're going to jump into the middle
所以我们要跳进中间
this the top level up and we'll focus
这个顶层起来，我们将重点关注
actually which will we focus on well
实际上 ，我们将专注于良好
we'll talk to some level in parallel
我们将讨论并行一定程度
because there's a lot of commonality as
因为有很多共性的作为
you can see between what goes on with
你可以看到之间有什么那张
the server and what goes on with the
服务器和发生的事情与
client and so actually the top level
客户端和所以实际上 的最高水平
called it's one called get adder info is
所谓它的一个名为get加法器的信息是
the way that it sort of initiates things
它那种 发起事物的方式
it actually does the the lookup to map
它实际上做的查找地图
from a domain name to a IP address so
从域名到IP地址 ，以便
we'll cover that later so the first step
我们将介绍一些后来所以第一步
in on either side then and creating a
在任一侧上，然后和创建
connection is a call to a function
连接是一个 函数 的调用
called socket and the reason I wanted to
所谓的插座，我想原因
Blackboard was to help you keep track of
黑板是帮助 您跟踪
so the first call is that doesn't do
所以第一个电话是不会做
much oh and that's why the function call
很多哦，这就是 为什么函数调用
is socket but the it only happens within
是插座，但只发生了内
the application it doesn't make a use of
应用它没有一个使用
any part of the operating system doesn't
操作系统的任何部分不
send anything over the network and the
发送任何东西在网络上和
idea is to basically say hey I want to
想法是基本上说，嘿，我想
create a takut and it's given three
创建takut和它给了3
arguments the first two which is AF
参数的前两个是AF
underscore I net all these uppercase R
强调我 净赚所有这些 大写的[R
names are constants that are built-in or
名字是被 内置 或常量
included in the various H files that you
包括在不同的 .h文件，你
include in writing this code and AF
包括在编写这些代码和AF
underscore I nut just means that say
强调我螺母只是表示说
ipv4 so 32-bit addresses and then the
的IPv4所以32位地址，然后将
second parameter is says you want a sock
第二个参数是说，你要 袜子
stream and that refers to a TCP
流和指 TCP
connection it's referred to as a stream
连接它的被称为流
connection because like I said you get
连接，因为就像我说的你
to send as many bytes as you like a
只要你喜欢一个 发送 的字节数
stream of bytes to in either direction
字节的流以在任一方向
and then
接着
zero protocol well I guess it must not
零协议 嗯，我想它 一定不能
be very interesting because I said it to
很有趣 ，因为我说的它
zero so we don't need to do anything in
零所以我们不需要 做任何事情在
this particular case there are man pages
这种特殊情况下也有手册页
on this by the way which if you just
在此顺便说一下它，如果你只是
tried to learn all sockets programming
努力学习 所有socket编程
by reading men pages you'd go crazy but
通过阅读网页的人，你会发疯 ，但
once you kind of have the idea of it
一旦你种有它的想法
the men pages are pretty useful and then
男人页面是非常有用的，然后
the next part you'll see we're looking
接下来的部分，你会看到，我们正在寻找
only now on the server side it's called
现在只在服务器端，它被称为
bind and
绑定和
what bind does then is that specific
什么绑定确实是那具体
then to a server and now this is a make
然后到一台服务器，现在这是一个让
this interfaces to the kernel it says I
这个接口给它说我的内核
want to
要
designate which IP address and let me
指定哪些IP地址，让我
just so I'm going to cheat a little bit
只是让我去骗一点点
I'm making sure I don't see anything
我确保我看不到任何东西
that's not true yeah I'm like sorry I
这不是真的，是我很喜欢我对不起
just want to make sure bind actually
只是想确保实际上绑定
tells you oh excuse me you'll see that a
告诉你哦， 对不起 ，你会看到一个
socket the call to socket returns an int
插座调用插座返回一个int
but it's what it's returning is a file
但它就是它的返回是一个文件
descriptor remember we said that if you
描述记得我们说， 如果你
refer to a file a low-level file just by
引用 文件的低级别的文件只是
an integer ID typically a small integer
一个整数ID通常是一个小整数
value there's some standard ones for
值有一些标准 药粥
standard in standard out standard air
在标准输出标准空气标准
and then beyond that they're just
然后除此之外 ，他们只是
assigned incrementally so socket will
增量分配，这样套接字
return a number that you then refer used
返回您再参考使用数
to refer to this as a file so bind then
指这是一个 文件，以便然后绑定
you pass in that the name of your socket
你传递你的插座名
file descriptor and you provide a
文件描述符你提供
whether is a socket adder ends
是否是一个插座加法器的端部
and si I'm using the the notation s si
和Si我使用的 符号S SI来
as a shortcut for sock adder struct sock
作为短袜加法器结构的袜子的快捷方式
adder and then you have to also say what
加法器，然后你也必须说些什么
the length of the address is so in the
该地址的长度是 这样的
case of ipv4 that would be four but you
IPv4的情况下，将有四个，但你
don't usually use that number directly
通常不 直接 使用该 号码
there's a we'll talk about it but that
有一个我们将谈论它，但是
top level call called gedit or header
顶级呼叫叫的gedit或头
info it's a relatively new API that was
信息是一个相对较新的API，这是
created and is in this edition of the
创建， 并在这一版的
book but not in previous ones is become
本书而 不是在以前的更是成为
the now the standard way that you get
现在 ，你得到 的标准方法
all the parameters that you're supposed
那你应该 将所有参数
to pass into all these different calls
传递到所有这些不同 的呼叫
and the idea of it then is it's a pretty
和它的想法则是这是一个非常
small adjustment to then write code
小调整，然后编写代码
that's good for either ipv4 or ipv6 so
这是很好的IPv4或IPv6等等
you don't normally give the actual
你通常不会给实际
number from that you get it from another
从您从 另一个 让它号
place in passages
发生在通道
so binding then is it's a kernel call
所以结合则是一个内核调用
that designates which particular service
其指定哪些特定服务
this program is going to be hosting or
这一计划将被托管或
which it will be the server for and
这将是服务器和
that's given by its port number
多数民众赞成 由它的端口号 给
and then the next step is to to listen
然后下一步就是要听
and that's just a call that says
这只是一个电话，说
that will now convert this socket to a
现在将这个插座转换为
listening socket which you need as a
监听套接字，你需要为
server so it's a way of telling the
服务器，以便它告诉的方式
kernel that this will be it will be a
内核，这将是这将 是一个
server-side
服务器端
so obviously bind and listen our related
所以很明显地结合并倾听我们的相关
ideas but you have to do both steps and
的想法，但你必须做两个步骤和
in that particular order to create a
在那个特定的顺序 创建
listening socket for one first server
对于一个第一服务器监听套接字
and then the final part of that to
然后的最终部分
operate it is to say except
操作它只是说
and
和
oh that means okay now we've established
哦，这意味着 现在没事了，我们已经建立
this now I'm actually ready to receive
这个现在我确实准备好接收
phone calls is essentially what it says
电话基本上是说话算数
this is the final step to say okay this
这是最后一步 说这没关系
one's ready to accept connection
一个已经准备好接受连接
requests and it has a similar set of
请求 和它有类似的一组
arguments to socket socket but slight
参数插座插座，但轻微
difference and now the interesting thing
差异而现在的有趣的事情
is acceptable return yet another file
是可以接受的回报另一个文件
descriptor now so the first file
现在描述这样的第一个文件
descriptor is the sort of generic accept
描述的是那种普通的接受
and basically accept we'll just hang
基本上接受我们只挂
there and wait until some client makes a
那里， 等到一些客户端发出
connection and when it does then it will
连接，当它然后它会
set up a new socket and a new with a new
建立一个新的套接字并用新新
file descriptor that then the server
文件描述符是那么服务器
communicates to the client via that one
通过一个到客户端通信
and I'll talk about why it's a different
我会谈谈为什么它是一个不同的
file descriptor in just a second okay
在短短的第二好文件描述符
over on the client side goes through
在客户端上的 经历
similar steps of socket but it doesn't
插座类似的步骤，但它不
have to bind or listen or accept because
要结合或听 或接受，因为
this is a client and instead what it
这是一个客户端，而是什么
does is it it makes a call to connect
所做的就是它使一个呼叫连接
so let me do this yourself so these are
所以让我这个做自己所以这些都是
all on the server side and on the client
所有在服务器端和客户端
side it will make a call to connect and
一边将拨打电话的连接和
that's its job of that is from a client
这是它 的那份 工作 是 从客户端
side is to set up a connection to server
一边是建立到服务器的连接
and so
所以
it's arguments it's a little easier to
它的 参数是一个更容易一些
understand how kynect works so in
了解kynect如何工作的，在
particular the call to socket
特别是吁请插座
that was made beforehand returns a file
这是事先做好返回一个文件
descriptor and what this says is I want
描述和它说的是我想
to on that particularly using that
到在该特别使用
particular socket connect to this gives
尤其是插座连接到这给
a combination of an address and a port
的地址和端口的组合
number and it has to give this address
数量和它给这个地址
length which I said like I said as
长度我说我等作为所述
before it's usually that number is
它通常是在此之前，号码是
filled in using the return value of get
填写使用get的返回值
a tour info but that's sort of the
旅游信息但这是排序的
equivalent of poisoning the cauldron and
中毒大锅的等效 ，
it returns just a code which is whether
它返回只是一个代码 是否 是
the connection was successful or not
连接成功与否
so let me just talk about these
所以让我来谈谈 这些
different ports and what it all means
不同的港口和这一切意味着什么
when you set up a connection so when the
当你建立了一个连接 ，以便当
the server went through bind and listen
服务器通过绑定去了， 听
it created a listening port from that
它从创建一个监听端口
which is the one that it's listening for
这是它的监听一个
connection requests on and then the
，然后连接请求
client when it called socket it was
客户端时，它被称为插座是
given a particular file descriptor for
给定一个特定的文件描述符
that net socket and it sends out a
净插座 ，它会 发出
connection request that goes out over
，超过外出连接请求
the network and lands at the server and
网络 和土地在服务器和
then the kernel hands that off to the
那么内核手中那关闭的
the the program that's running on that
在那个关于这一运行的程序
particular port and hands it off to the
特定的端口并把它关到
ik that call will be handled by the
IK该呼叫将被处理
accept call to accept by the server and
接受呼叫服务器接受并
then as I mentioned except actually
然后我实际上除了提到
returns a new file descriptor which the
返回一个新的文件描述符的
server will then use as its connection
然后服务器将其连接使用
point to this particular client and the
点这个特殊的客户端，
theory of that is you want to be able to
那理论是要 能够
in general as a server be handling
一般 作为服务器 来处理
multiple clients at the same time but if
在同一时间，但如果多个客户端
I'm communicating with with Google or
我与与谷歌或通信
Amazon you should be able to do so at
亚马逊你应该能够这样做
the same time so you want a possibility
同时让你想 有一个可能性
of from a single host to be able to
从一台 主机能够
serve multiple clients and that's why
服务于多个客户端，这就是为什么
they're all assigned different file
他们都分配了不同的文件
descriptors at the server end for that
在对服务器端描述
particular connection so you can think
特定的连接，所以你能想到的
of it as the listening file descriptor
它作为监听的文件描述符
is just listening for incoming requests
只是监听传入的请求
for connections but once it sets up a
为连接，但一旦它建立了一个
session and communicates back and forth
会议并传达来回
those are going through different ports
那些正在经历不同的端口
on the server side of things or
对 事物的 服务器端 或
different file descriptions I'm sorry
不同的 文件描述对不起
same port different file descriptors
同一端口不同的文件描述符
from the software that's running on the
从对正在运行的软件
server
服务器
okay and then during the actual
好吧，然后在 实际
communication then as I mentioned it
通信然后正如我 所提到它
uses reads and writes as a way to send
使用读取和写入的方式来发送
and receive messages and that goes on
和接收消息并 继续
for as long as you know and according to
只要你知道 ，并根据
whatever lo of particular protocol is
任何特定协议的LO是
being supported by this application and
此应用程序所支持和
then in the end then when the client the
然后在端则当客户端的
client is done it closes the request and
客户端做了关闭请求 ，
what that looks like from the server end
它们的样子， 从服务器端
is it tries to read from a file and it
是它试图从一个文件，它读取
receives an into file a signal instead
接收到文件 ，而不是 一个信号
and that tells the server okay this
并告诉服务器这没关系
particular connection is is gone and so
具体的连接 已经一去不复返了 ，因此
now it will close that particular one as
现在它将关闭 特定的一个 作为
this picture shows here potentially the
这幅画 的潜在这里显示
server could loop back around and accept
服务器可以循环回到我的身边，接受
a connection from another program and in
从另一个 程序，并在 连接
fact this can be done this is what we
其实这是可以做到这 就是我们
call a serial or entered a serial server
调用一个串行或进入串口服务器
where it can only manage one connection
它只能管理一个连接
request at a time and when we get later
要求在同一时间 ，当我们后来得到
in the course and we talk talk about
在使用过程中，我们聊谈
multi-threading we'll be able to set it
多线程，我们就可以将其设置
up so this thing can start accepting
了这么这个东西可以开始受理
requests for another connection even
另一个连接请求甚至
while it's handling one particular
而它的处理 一个特定的
client but anyways what it will look
客户端，但它反正会 看 什么
like is the server will read the attempt
就像是服务器将读取的尝试
to read that will get an into file it
阅读， 将获得一个 进入文件时，它
will close that particular connection
将关闭该 特定连接
and it will go back and it will accept a
它会回去 ，它会接受
new connection from a new client
从一个新的客户端新连接
okay I'm going to jump ahead and
好吧，我要跳进取，
actually start talking about some slides
其实开始 谈论一些幻灯片
from that we're if you look online
从，如果你在网上看我们
they're actually from a Thursday's
它们实际上是从周四
lecture because there's a lot of ground
讲座，因为有很多的理由
to cover in that lecture and I'd like to
在讲座 覆盖 ， 我想
get a little head start so I mentioned
得到一点点 的 开端，所以我 提到的
this this function called get a door
这个这个函数调用得到一个门
info which is sort of the modern way in
信息是某种 现代方式
C at least to find information about
C中的至少找到 有关 信息
that deals with all the funkiness of
与 所有的funkiness 交易
host names host addresses all the
主机名主机地址全部
conventions about ports and some of
有关端口和一些约定
these various structures and things like
这些不同的结构之类的东西
that and the advantage of doing it this
这一点， 做这个 的优势
way instead of the old way is first of
方式，而不是旧的方式是先
all now it's 30 unifies ipv4 and ipv6
所有现在是30统一IPv4和IPv6
have very similar looking interfaces and
有非常相似的 找接口，
it's fairly easy to write code that can
它很容易编写的代码 ， 可以
handle either and the other words there
处理任何一种，其余的单词有
is problems with these old ones that
与这些旧 的问题，
they were designed in an era before
它们被设计在一个时代 之前
multi-threading and so they have a very
多线程，所以他们有一个非常
aesthetically allocated buffers which
美观分配的缓冲区，其
gave a lot of bad conditions that you
给了很多恶劣的条件下，你
had to watch out for in writing code and
曾在编写 代码来监视 并
we're prone to errors of various sorts
我们倾向于各种种类的错误
and so this new new format it's actually
所以这个新的新的格式，它实际上
harder to use in many levels because it
难 在许多层面上 使用 ，因为它
can't hide away as many details as it
无法遁形 的很多细节，因为 它
used to but it has the advantage it
来适应，但它的优势在于它
works better in a multi-threaded
工作在多线程更好
environment the other thing that makes
环境，使得其他的事情
it hard is it's trying to be sort of the
难 是它试图要排序的
kitchen sink of of protocol managers and
的协议管理器厨房水槽和
that makes it a little bit nasty and
这使得它有点讨厌和
messy and so we're only going to sort of
乱，所以我们只是要排序的
focus in on the parts that we really
聚焦于 部分，我们真的
need to make use of for this course
需要使用本课程
so in particular there's this function
所以特别是有 这个功能
called get a dirt info where the
所谓获得 灰尘信息的地方
information you're passing is a host
你传递的信息是主机
which can be either a it's a string as
它可以是一个这是一个字符串
it shows most these are care stars are
这表明大多数这些都是护理星星
actual real strings not fake strings it
实际真正的字符串不是假的串它
used to be back in the old days you use
曾经是早在 你用过去的日子
care stars a generic pointer because
护理星辰通用指针，因为
there weren't void stars but these are
有没有空隙明星，但这些都是
actual strings so you give the name like
实际的字符串，这样你给喜欢的名字
the the domain name of a host or you can
主机的域名，或者你可以
give the dotted decimal name but written
给点分十进制名称，但写
as you know sequence of characters one
你知道 一个 字符序列
two aches dot so forth a service for
2个酸痛点等 为 服务
example that this is ipv4 to TCP service
例如，这是IPv4 向TCP服务
some other information that that's
其他一些信息 这
associated with this particular
与此相关联的特定
connection they refer to as hints
连接他们称之为 提示
because again this is trying to be a
因为这同样 是试图 成为一个
very generic looking call and then you
非常通用的寻找电话，然后你
pass it in a pointer and it will fill in
通过它的指针，它会填写
and return back a pointer to a data
并返回一个指针回数据
structure which is essentially the way
结构，该结构基本上与方法
it's returning results back to you and
它的返回结果反馈给你，
then associated with that is a call
然后与 相关的 是呼叫
called free adder info that will then
所谓的自由加法资讯，以再
deallocate this face that's used by this
取消此分配脸上那的二手本
data structure from the result and then
从结果的数据，然后结构
there's one called get adder info string
有一个名为get加法器信息串
error which lets you interpret the
错误它可以让你解释
various error code to get created by
得到通过创建各种错误代码
this routine of the value that it
它的价值这个例程
returns so
所以返回
let's just look a little about this and
就让我们看看一些关于这一点，
so the result that's returned by get a
所以这返回的结果得到
door info is a linked list that is null
门信息是一个链表 是空
terminated which is like most linguists
终止其是最喜欢的 语言学家
are where it gives some combination of
在哪里它给人的某种组合
the name of this particular some naming
这个特殊的一些命名的名称
information for the the first top-level
对于第一个顶级信息
one is the what I showed you the
一个是什么， 我向您展示了
canonical name for this particular IP
这个特定IP规范名称
address and then it gives some address
地址，然后它给一些地址
information which is you know an ipv4
这是你知道一个IPv4信息
them that will encode the IP address and
他们将编码IP地址和
as a next pointer to change this link
作为下一个指针来改变这种链接
both together and so this is actually
两者一起 ，因此这实际上是
one interesting thing about this is it
这一个有趣的事情是它
sort of takes care of that many too many
排序的照顾，许多 太多 的
mapping potentially of of names so if I
映射的潜在 名 的 ，所以如果我
give for example google.com it will
给例如google.com 它会
return a link twist of all however many
然而返回所有很多的链接扭曲
or
要么
you saw with Twitter it was returning
您与Twitter看到它返航
about four different addresses so this
大约四个不同的地址，所以这
will return actually five list entries
实际上将返回五个列表条目，
the first will be the canonical name and
第一个将是标准名称，并
then it will give each of the four IP
然后它会给四个 IP的
addresses that relevant at this
解决了有关在这一点，
particular time and then you as a
特定的时间，然后你作为一个
programmer than to walk this list you
程序员不是走这个名单你
step down this list and typically try to
下台此列表 ，通常会尝试
use each address one after the other and
使用后，其他每个地址之一 ，
if you fail on one then you try the next
如果你没有一个那么你尝试下
and try the next until you hit the end
和尝试下，直到 你打 到底
of the list and then you say whoops
列表中的，然后你说哎呦
can't do it
不能做到这一点
and that goes whether you're writing a
和去无论你写
client or a server so that adder info
客户端或服务器，使加法信息
let's look back at what that is oh so
让我们回头 看看 那 是 什么 哦如此
adder in fo then is what gets returned
加法器FO则是被返回了什么
is a list of adder info structs and so
是加法器的信息结构等的列表
the adder info struct contains various
加法器信息结构包含各种
fields which talks about what type of
其中谈到什么类型的字段
data is here what type of socket is it
数据是在这里什么类型的插座是
what its canonical name is how long are
什么它的规范 名称是有多长
its addresses you saw that it's an
你看到了它的地址，它是一个
argument to some of the calls a pointer
争论的一些 呼叫指针
to a sock adder struct that's the way
到袜子加法器结构 是这样的方式
that is encoded for IPV what we've
被编码为 IPV我们已经
already seen sock adders is a sort of
已经看到袜子加法器是一种的
low-level data structure that gets used
该被 使用 的低级数据结构
and then a next pointer to chain the
然后下一个指针链中的
link twist together and so you'll see
链接 扭结，所以你会看到
some of these are the arguments that
其中 也 不乏一些 的论点，即
then you will use to pass into the other
那么你 会用 传递到其他
functions like bind and whitson and
像结合和 惠特森和功能
connect
连
and then there's another version called
然后还有另一个 叫 版本
get name info which you use when you've
获得当你您所使用的名称信息
got an IP address and you want to find
得到一个IP地址，你想找到
what is it
它是什么
domain name and because you remember
域名，因为你还记得
that mapping is also potentially a
该映射是也潜在一个
one-to-many there can be multiple domain
一个一对多可以有多个域
names associated with it and so it has a
与之 相关联的名字，所以 它有一个
similar general thing we'll just look
我们就类似于普通的事
right now it get editor info so just as
现在它得到 的编辑信息 ，以便就如同
an example of how you'd write code to
你会如何编写代码示例
make use of this and essentially just as
利用这一点，基本上只是作为
a way of probing the DNS server is I
探测DNS服务器的方式是 我
want to set up an argument a call to get
想成立一个参数调用获得
adder info where the string I'm going to
加法器的信息，其中字符串我要去
pass the name is whatever I type in at
通过名字无论我在输入
the to this application to main and it
在这个应用程序主要和它
just for hints just passes a bunch of
只是提示只是传递了一堆
zeros and lists P again these are this
零和 列表P又一次，这些都是本
will just be a pointers that I haven't
将只是一个指针， 我有不
actually
其实
oh okay so you'll notice hints is
哦， 好吧，你会发现提示是
actually a struct itself whereas with T
实际上一个结构本身，而以T
and star P are just list P and P are
和明星P为刚 列表P和P
just pointers to structs they don't have
仅用于指向结构，他们没有
any allocated data so the hints I'm just
任何分配的数据，所以提示我只是
going to fill in that struct with all
要填写与所有的结构
zeros because I don't really need to
零，因为我 并不真的需要
provide any hints I am telling it that I
提供我告诉它我任何提示
want a an ipv6 TCP connection here and
希望这里的IPv6的TCP连接，并
then so what it will do is it will
那还等什么，将要做的是将
return back
返回回
what returns an error code but it will
什么返回错误代码，但它会
fill in return to me a pointer to a this
填写回给我一个指向该
link twist data structure I showed
链接扭曲数据结构，我发现
before and now I can step through that
之前，现在我可以通过一步
list using standard linked list code and
使用标准的 链表代码列表
make calls to the get name info function
做出的get名信息的函数调用
which will return back domain names
这将返回域名
and then when it's all done I have to
然后当这一切都完成我必须
free up that whisk that got returned
腾出得到返回的是拂尘
otherwise I'll create memory stuff so
否则我将创建存储的东西，所以
just as a demo
只是作为一个演示
come on
来吧
so host in closer ah so you can think of
所以主办仔细 啊，所以你能想到的
it this is like a not very fancy
它这 就像一个不是很花哨
implementation of nslookup so the kind
实现了nslookup这样的那种
of stuff we already saw before but let's
的东西，我们已经看到 过，但让我们
all its returning are the different
所有的返回是不同的
addresses and one of the things that I
地址和的事情之一，我
found curious is it returns them in the
发现好奇的是它返回他们在
same order all the time instead of
同一顺序所有的时间，而不是
within its lookup it kept changing it
它查找 在 它不停地 变化着 它
and I think that has to do with caching
我认为有缓存办
no I changed I know it's kind of
不，我改变了我知道 这是一种
interesting if it's you might want to
有趣的，如果 它是你可能要
play with this code it's kind of you can
与此代码玩它是一种 可以
see what's going on in different places
看看发生了什么 事情在不同的地方
and so you can see though that it's
所以你可以看到，虽然它的
basically getting the same kind of
基本上得到相同类型的
information that you would from nslookup
信息， 你从NSLOOKUP会
Detroit is creating the DNS server to do
底特律创建DNS服务器 做
this but that's the start of what some
这种但是这是一些什么样的开始
of this code looks like
这个代码看起来 像
and
和
one of the things you by the way when
的事情，你的方式，当一个
you're writing your own code you often
你 是否经常 编写自己的 代码
make use of what's called localhost and
利用什么叫做 本地主机，
that's always just refers to the machine
这始终只是指机
that you're running on it always has
那你 就可以运行总是有
this particular IP address so that
这个特殊的IP地址，以便
address just refers to the machine and
地址只是指机
as a programmer you do all your testing
作为一个程序员，你做你的测试
on one machine you just set up both the
一台机器上，你刚刚 成立的两
client and the server on the same
客户端和在同一服务器
machine and play with it so localhost is
机并使用它使本地主机是
a very useful way of doing code
做代码的一个非常有用的方式
development and as this shows you can
发展 ，因为 这表明你可以
request host info for others thanksgivin
为他人thanksgivin请求主机信息
and you can also by the way
你顺便也可以
always give a dotted decimal address
总是给点分十进制地址
I'm just making it up here but it's not
我只是做 它在这里，但它不是
very interesting because it returns back
非常有趣，因为它返回
to the same address it's more
对同一地址它更
interesting to to run nslookup on that
有趣的要上运行nslookup
so that just gives you a sense and as
使刚刚给你的 感觉 和
you've seen this code is pretty messy
你已经看到了这个代码是相当混乱
stuff to work with there's a lot of
东西与那里工作的很多
structs you have to initialize you don't
结构你必须初始化你不
initialize your pass pointers and so the
初始化指针传递等等
code always looks a bit crusty but that
代码总是看起来有点脾气暴躁但
sort of the the interfaces it exists and
排序它存在的接口和
you'll just have to get somewhat
你只需要拿到几分
comfortable with it so that will do it
舒服 ，这样会 做
for today then thanks
今天再感谢